

Full-time Professor of Information Systems Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (IFRN) 1692 Dr. Nilo Bezerra Ramalho St.

Tirol – 59015-300 Natal – RN – Brazil

Website: http://www.ifrn.edu.br

E-mails: jalerson@gmail.com | jalerson.lima@ifrn.edu.br

Homepage: http://jalerson.me TOEFL Score: 91 points

Summary

Professor of Information Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Basics at the Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte. Researcher at the Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare. Master in Systems and Computing at the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte. Currently looking for job or PhD oportunities abroad, specially in Canada, United States, Europe or Australia.

Research Interests

Software Engineering: Empirical software engineering, collaboration-based software development, software developers productivity assessment, mining software repositories.

Classroom and Remote Education: Computer programming, software engineering concepts and practices.

Informatics in Healthcare.

Current Activities

Since 2010: Professor of Information Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Basics Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2012: Researcher of Remote Healthcare

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)
Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Previous Experience

2009 - 2010: Systems Analyst

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2009: Substitute Professor of Information Systems

Natal Campus (http://portal.ifrn.edu.br/campus/natalcentral)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

2008 – 2009: Remote Systems Analyst Consultant

Symetrix Corp. (http://www.symetrixcorp.com/)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2005 - 2007: Scientific Initiation Researcher

Natal Campus (http://portal.ifrn.edu.br/campus/natalcentral)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

2005 – 2006: Scientific Initiation Researcher

Natal Campus

Feveral University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Education

2012 – 2014: Master's degree in Systems and Computing

Department of Computing and Applied Mathematics (https://dimap.ufrn.br/en)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2008 – 2010: Specialization's degree (Post-Bachelor qualification) in Systems Engineering

Open Superior School of Brazil (http://www.esab.edu.br)

Vila Velha, Espirito Santo, Brazil

2004 – 2007: Bachelor's degree in Software Development

Academic Department of Management and Information Technology (http://diatinf.ifrn.edu.br)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

Projects

2014: Macau EXPOTEC Website, PHP Project

Macau Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2013: Backhoe, Master's degree project developed in Java

Department of Computing and Applied Mathematics (https://dimap.ufrn.br/en)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2013: Nova Cruz EXPOTEC Website, PHP Project

Nova Cruz Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2012: Telepediatria, Ruby on Rails project

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2012: National Observatory of Dengue, Ruby on Rails project (AFP Video: http://youtu.be/kWvhaHXv-70)

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2011: Pau dos Ferros EXPOTEC Website, Ruby on Rails project

Pau dos Ferros Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

2009 – 2010: Telepesquisa, Ruby on Rails project

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2009 – 2010: Bluesync, Java project

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2008: RFID-based projects, Java, C# and .NET projects

Ciclop

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2008: Eye of the Eagle, C# and C project *Symetrix Corp.* (http://www.symetrixcorp.com/) *Colorado Springs, Colorado, United States*

2007: Portal Conexões de Saberes, Java project

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2006: Recarcine, PHP project

Brazilian Agency of Aquaculture Development

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Publications

Summary published in proceedings of conferences

Development of a system to support pediatric diabetic patients using Brazilian Remote Healthcare Program

Ricardo Arrais, Jalerson Lima, Jailton Carlos, Ricardo Valentim

10th Brazilian Congress of Pediatric Endrocrinology and Metabolism, 2013

Papers in scientific journals

Dengue National Observatory - A system for dengue cases monitoring

Daniele Montenegro da Silva Barros, Philippi Sedir Grilo de Morais, Jailton Carlos de Paiva, Jalerson Raposo Ferreira de Lima, Janaína Luana Rodrigues da Silva

Journal of Technological Innovation in Healthcare, 2013

XRTPS - Extensible Real-Time Publish-Subscribe: A multicast middleware for exchanging XML-based data in real time networks

Jalerson Raposo Ferreira de Lima, Ricardo Alexsandro de Medeiros Valentim, Bruno Gomes de Araújo, João Marcos Teixeira Lacerda, Diego Rodrigues de Carvalho, Marcel da Câmara Ribeiro Dantas, Ronaldo Maia de Medeiros

HOLOS, 2011

Complete works published in proceedings of conferences

Assessing Developer Contribution with Repository Mining-based Metrics

Jalerson Lima, Christoph Treude, Fernando Figueira, Uirá Kulesza

31st International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME), 2015

Conditional Execution: A Pattern for the Implementation of Fine-Grained Variabilities in Software Product Lines

Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Gleydson Lima, Uirá Kulesza, Demóstenes Sena, Felipe Pinto, Alexandre Vianna, David Pereira, Victor Fernandes

9th Latin-American Conference on Pattern Languages of Programming, 2012

Modularization of Variabilities From Software Product Lines of Web Information Systems

Demóstenes Sena, Felipe Pinto, Gleydson Lima, Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Uirá Kulesza, David Pereira, Victor Fernandes, Alexandre Vianna

9th Latin-American Conference on Pattern Languages of Programming, 2012

Squid: an extensible infrastructure for analyzing software product line implementations

Alexandre Vianna, Felipe Pinto, Demóstenes Sena, Uirá Kulesza, Roberta Coelho, Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Gleydson Lima

3rd International Workshop on Knowledge Oriented Product Line Engineering, 2012

Teaching

Remote Education

Academic Semester 2015.2

Remote Education Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Structured and Object-Oriented Programming

Academic Semester 2015.1

Remote Education Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Design Web
Algorithms

Academic Semester 2014.2

Remote Education Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
New Information and Communication Technologies and Moodle in Education
Computer Basics

Academic Semester 2014.1

Remote Education Campus Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil Computer Basics

Classroom

Academic Semester 2013.2

Nova Cruz Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Web Development Fundamentals
Project Development
Internet Programming Fundamentals
Internet Programming with Database

Academic Semester 2013.1

Nova Cruz Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Web Development Fundamentals
Algorithms
Internet Programming Fundamentals
Web Programming

Academic Semester 2012.2

Nova Cruz Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Algorithms
Computer Basics
Web Programming

Academic Semester 2012.1

João Câmara Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Algorithms
Object-Oriented Programming

Nova Cruz Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Databases
Algorithms
Object-Oriented Programming

Academic Semester 2011.2

Currais Novos Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Programming Fundamentals
Software Engineering
Computer Basics

Academic Semester 2011.1

Pau dos Ferros Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Programming Fundamentals
Web Development Fundamentals
Web Programming
Developing Web Applications using Java

Academic Semester 2010.2

Pau dos Ferros Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
Computer Basics
Web Development Fundamentals
Programming Fundamentals
Object-Oriented Programming

Academic Semester 2010.1

Pau dos Ferros Campus
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil
BrOffice Workshop
Computer Basics (Nutrition course)
Web Development Fundamentals
Algorithms

Supervised Students

Technical Degree

Ailson Barbosa de Oliveira Open-source solutions for e-commerce

Anderson Rodrigues de Sousa

Developing a system for EXPOTEC enrolment management

Nathália Thais Trajano da Fonsêca Silva Modeling a system for academic activities management

Bruno Agenor Soares Santana Margaret Darling Bezerra An online and collaborative system for manage educational materials

Joel Fernandes Cardoso dos Santos João Oliveira da Silva Júnior A system for academic activities management

Josivânia Kelly Flôr de Lima Silva Renata de Souza Lima *Robocode Tournament*

Maria Gracielly F. Coutinho Rubiany Farias Mendes Producing didatic materials for Scratch: a support tool to teach programming

Camila Karen Silva Jacó Renata Pereira Padilha do Rosário IFRN Egressos: An online system to offer and seek jobs